-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=-
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 影子
翻译: Morning 脸圆圆 RK翔 汐颜 倒数第二的yjk 雪鸢域寰
校对: 千欲 秋水仙
eHarmony: 网恋网 美国最大的婚恋交友网站之一
我的理想男友: 爱冒险 有勇气 有创造力(或有工作)
喜欢: 我的姐姐 悬疑小说  不喜欢: 我的妹妹 网恋
你应该了解: 我有一只三条腿的狗... 和一个两条腿的孩子
对她示好
无法执行请求
嗯?
Huh?
你好! 我是网恋网的托德·马哈尔
Hi! Todd Mahar, eHarmony.
今天有什么能为您效劳?
How can I help you today?
你好 我好像无法给别人发送表情
Hi. I can't seem to leave a wink for someone.
我不知道 是我的页面崩溃了吗?
I don't know, is my page broken?
是否进入了错误的页面 或者...
Do I maybe have a broken page, or...
我从没遇到这种情况 但是没关系
I've never heard of that, but, okay.
你是第一次使用你的网恋网账户吗?
You're trying to use your eHarmony account for the first time?
- 是的  - 好的
- I am.  - Okay.
我正在看你的简介
I'm looking at your profile.
我们有一个非常复杂的匹配算法
We have a pretty intricate matching algorithm.
这是我们和其他在线交友网站
That's what distinguishes us from other
不一样的地方
online dating services.
没错 我欣赏这一点
Yeah, I like that.
其实 我只是想给一个人发送表情
Actually, I'm just trying to leave a wink for one person.
她叫谢尔·梅霍芙
Cheryl Melhoff.
她在一个月前进入我的部门工作...
She started in my division at work about a month ago...
我偶然在面包店附近听她说
and I overheard her near the bagels
她在你们网站征婚
saying she was on your site.
好吧 真特别的情况
Okay, that's unique.
但我想问个问题
But let me ask you.
你有很多项...
You left a lot of this stuff...
比如"你的经历"的部分空着没填
like the "Been There, Done That" section, you left it blank.
没错 我跳过了这部分
Yeah, I think I skipped it.
好吧 你不能为难我 先生
Okay, you got to help me out here, man.
不要省略信息
Don't skip stuff.
好吧 但是我真没去过
Okay, well, I haven't really been
任何有名或值得一提地方
anywhere noteworthy or mentionable.
有没有你曾做过值得一提的事情?
Have you done anything noteworthy, mentionable?
你好 你还在听吗?
Hello, you still there?
你能稍等一下吗?
Can you hang on a second?
快 快 快! 让开! 让开!
Go, go, go! Get out! Get out!
快爆炸啦! 快走! 快走!
She's gonna blow! Go! Go!
- 奇普!  - 在这里!
- Chips!  - Over here!
奇普! 谢谢!
Chips! Thank you!
你怎么知道这楼会爆炸?
How did you know about the building?
我听到犬吠声 还闻到了煤气味
I heard barking, thought I smelled gas.
但愿它没事
I hope it's okay.
我在冲下楼梯的时候
I engineered a prosthesis for Chips
顺便给奇普做了一个假肢
while I was sprinting down the stairwell.
一个固定在臀部
A little hip-joint assembly
套在前骨盘 还有垂环锁的小假肢
with a drop-ring lock and an anterior pelvic band.
天啊 你真让人刮目相看!
God, you're noteworthy!
我是三有青年: 有魄力 有勇气 有创造力
I just live by the ABC's: Adventurous, Brave, Creative.
这就是我理想中的男人啊
That's everything I want in a man.
先生?
My man?
嘿 先生 你还在听吗?
Hey, my man, you still there?
嘿
Hey.
怎么了? 你是晕过去了还是...
What? Did you pass out or...
不是 我只是出神了
No, I just like, zoned out for a second.
好吧 你经常这样吗?
Okay. Do you do that a lot?
我想 也就普通频率
Normal amount, I guess.
我得走了 抱歉
Yeah, I got to run. Sorry.
好吧 但我们需要更多的...
Okay, but we need a lot more...
白日梦想家
嘿 今天可不是迟到的好日子
Hey. Bad day to be late.
我们公司刚刚被收购了
We just got acquired.
- 什么?  - 是的 就在周末
- What?  - Yeah, over the weekend.
华特! 生日快乐!
Walter! Happy birthday!
喔呼!
Whoo-hoo!
他四十二岁了!
He's 42 years old!
欧黛纱! 你来这里干嘛?
Odessa! What are you doing here?
你妈做了你最喜欢的小柑橘蛋糕
Mom made you your favorite clementine cake.
你不是应该在养老院
Aren't you supposed to be at the retirement place
帮妈把钢琴搬进去吗?
with her getting the piano moved in?
没错 我在那里 干完差不多一半了...
Yes, I was there. It's like halfway done...
把钢琴从货车里搬出来 在街上放着 一切都很顺利
piano's out of the van, it's on the street, everything's fine.
但我刚好接了个很重要的试镜
But I just got a phone call about a really
所以你能帮我搬钢琴吗?
big audition, so can you go finish it?
- 不行 我要迟到了  - 华特 我...
- No, I can't. I'm late.  - Walter, I...
我觉得你没明白我需要什么
I don't think you're seeing this from what I need.
你需要什么?
What do you need?
我要成为"火爆浪子"里的里佐
I need to be Rizzo in Grease.
1978年出品的电影 改编自音乐剧"西边故事"
我没明白
I don't understand that.
- 我的试镜! 里佐!  - 里佐?
- My audition! Rizzo!  - Rizzo?
里佐! 她既强硬又温柔!
Rizzo! She's tough and tender!
里佐是个叛逆女孩 试图用强硬的外表掩盖痛苦和自卑
放过我吧 求你了
Do me a favor, please.
不管你用什么办法 一定要把妈妈的钢琴搬进去 好吗?
Make sure Mom's piano gets moved in all the way. All right?
不要当里佐!
Don't go to Rizzo!
谢你全家 华特 生日快乐!
Oh, thanks, Walter. Happy birthday!
知道吗? 我们刚刚被收购了
Guess what? We just got acquired.
是的 我听说了
Yeah, I heard.
而且要做一些调动
Yeah, there's gonna be changes.
很可能会把我们下调到一些网络部门去
Downsizing of us into some kind of dot-com thing, possibly.
真是前途未卜
I wonder how this thing goes down,
过渡期又该怎么过
how the transition's gonna play out.
我也许能告诉你
I could probably tell you.
我是泰德·亨德里克斯 过渡期的主管经理
Ted Hendricks, managing director of the transition.
你好 我是蒂姆·诺顿 销售部
Hey. Tim Naughton. Sales.
我是加里·曼海姆 平面设计部
Gary Mannheim, graphic design.
你是做什么的 蛋糕师?
And what do you do, cake man?
哦 呃...
Oh, uh...
这蛋糕只是今天才有 我不是蛋糕师
The cake's just for today. I'm not a cake man.
我是做...
I do...
我这接负责...
I deal dirctly...
"这接"?
"Dirctly"?
处理"生活"杂志的所有图片...
Directly with LIFE's photo units...
不好意思 我完全沉浸在这首歌里
I'm sorry, I was really getting into this song
没听见你说什么
and I stopped listening to you.
我刚刚说 你知道谁留胡子好看吗?
I was saying, you know who looks good in a beard?
是邓布利多 不是你
Dumbledore, not you.
邓布利多: 出自"哈利·波特"系列
伙计?
Guy?
你是做什么的?
What do you do?
我是底片资产部的经理
I'm a negative asset manager.
看你表现咯
Worth the wait.
# 楞个里格楞 #
# Mind over matter #
- 嘿 泰德  - 唐尼
- Ted.  - Donny.
- 还适应吗?  - 非常好
- Feeling tough?  - Feeling good.
嗯 以后还得做不少艰难决定呢
Well, got to make some tough calls ahead.
你之前来过这里 是吗?
You been here before, yeah?
嗯 感觉这儿怎么样?
Yeah, so this is it, huh?
感觉像是"照片屋"
Yeah, the "house of pictures."
嘿
Hey.
- 嗨  - 周末过得怎样?
- Hi.  - How was your weekend?
这个周末糟透了
I had an awesome weekend.
这个周末你都做了什么?
And what did you do this weekend?
唔... 我想想
Um... Let's see.
我用北极冰泉泡了个澡...
I bathed in Arctic mountain water...
我的拉丁情人在一旁背诗给我听
while my Latin lover recited verse to me.
- 真会意淫  - 对吧
- You slut.  - I know.
事实上 我在等冰箱修理工 可他一直没有来
Actually, I waited for my refrigerator repairman, who never came.
真悲剧
I'm so sorry.
晚点给你打电话
I'm gonna call you later.
好的
Okay.
冰 对吧?
The ice, yes?
她就像女人一样无常
She moves like a woman.
我叫华特·米蒂
I'm Walter Mitty.
我叫谢尔·梅霍芙
Cheryl Melhoff.
你去哪里了?
Where have you been?
测试人类精神的极限
Testing the limits of the human espirit.
我想爬上你的头发 测试一下
I'd like to climb your hair, test that out.
我可以用我的传情猎鹰跟你联系
Perhaps I can contact you, possibly through my poetry falcon.
传情猎鹰
Poetry falcon.
我喜欢这名字
I like that.
要是我拿回形针打他一下 他会不会动呢?
Do you think, if I hit him with a paper clip, would he move?
不知道
I don't know.
试试
Do it.
来
Hello.
我曾经真的朝他扔过一个墨盒
I actually threw a toner box at him once.
是吗? 他动了吗?
Yeah? Did he move?
没有 我扔偏了
No, I missed.
真是个好故事
That's a great story.
塔台呼叫汤姆上校
Ground Control to Major Tom.
你能听见吗 汤姆上校?
Can you hear me, Major Tom?
哦!
Oh!
哇
Wow.
我们接着往下说
Moving on, as they say.
这是会议室 这边是办公室...
Conference room, more of these stations here...
大部分时间员工各干各的
where people sort of do their thing.
这样布局是为了...
Layout's here for...
早上好 赫南多!
Morning, Hernando!
新来了个难缠的家伙 你听说了吗?
There's a new nut pouch, did you hear?
是的 我见过他了
Yeah. I met him.
我们要被重新考核
We're gonna be evaluated.
不过他们考核不了 我们这活还是很难的
They won't be able to. We do intricate details back here.
没错
Yeah.
这活很麻烦 而且容易出错
It's tricky. And bewildering.
应该让我们互相考核
I should evaluate you, you should evaluate me.
我觉得他们不会让我们这么做的
I don't think they'll let us do that.
说说而已
Just saying.
这卷底片放在这里多久了?
Hey, how long has this neg roll been here?
放在外面的这卷
Out in the open.
上面写着"肖恩·奥康奈尔"
It says "Sean O'Connell."
今天早上拿来的
It came in this morning.
还有个礼物 他寄给你一份礼物 就在你桌上
There's a present, too. He sent you a present, on your desk.
肖恩·奥康奈尔还在用胶卷拍照
Sean O'Connell still shoots on film.
我真是很喜欢他
That results for me in a man crush.
嘿 你想洗这盒胶卷吗?
Hey, you want to mount these?
真的我来?
Seriously?
当然
Sure.
听说"生活"杂志破产了
Heard rumblings LIFE's done, man.
我想对你道谢
Wanted to say thanks.
看看里面的东西 作为你多年努力工作的礼物
Take a look inside, a gift for all the years of hard work.
至于底片胶卷 我很抱歉
Sorry about the neg roll.
我自己缝合...
I spilled some blood on it...
腹部枪伤的时候 溅了点血在胶卷上面...
while self-stitching a gun wound to my abdomen...
但二十五号是我拍得最好的一张
but number 25 is my best ever.
我认为是生活的精髓
The quintessence of life, I think.
我相信你会把它放在属于它的位置上...
I trust you'll get it where it needs to go...
你总能做到
you always do.
感谢你所做的一切
你拿的是什么?
What did you get?
钱包
It's a wallet.
有"生活"杂志的格言在上面
With LIFE's motto on it.
认识世界 克服困难
洞悉所有 贴近生活
寻找真爱 感受彼此
这就是生活的意义
给你
Here you go.
- 二十五号呢?  - 没有
- Where's 25?  - It's not there.
嘿 我们需要二十五号底片
Hey, we need negative 25.
肖恩·奥康奈尔发了电报
Sean O'Connell sent a telegram.
是真的电报
An actual telegram.
一个带着小帽子的百岁老人传信的
A 100-year-old dude came in a little hat.
所以要开个楼层会议
So there's a floor meeting.
带上二十五号底片
Bring 25.
肯定还在这 我们会找到它的
It's here somewhere. We'll find it.
好的 尽快制作这些框架的关系表
Okay, make a contact sheet of these frames as soon as you can.
而且别跟任何人提起这事
And don't say anything to anyone.
好的
Yeah.
我很不情愿地要通知大家...
I just wanted to inform you all reluctantly, that...
我想得重头再说一遍
I guess, just start back from the beginning.
好了 我很不情愿地要通知大家...
Okay. I just wanted to inform you all reluctantly...
本月的期刊将会是我们的最后一期
that this month's issue will be our last.
什么?
What?
是的 什么?
Yeah. What?
扯淡!
This is some bull!
是坏消息...
It's sad...
确实如此
news, for sure.
你们都是难得的好员工
Now, you're all valued employees.
但由于我们处于"生活"杂志网络化的过渡期...
But as we undergo this transition to LIFE online...
所以我们想明白告诉你们...
we wanted to be candid with you...
将有部分员工被新公司...
that some of you will be determined non-vital employees...
列为非重要员工
to the new partnership.
而我们将在下周的例会上...
And we'll be deciding which of those positions...
决定保留哪些职位
will be remaining with us over the course of the next week.
正如你所见 我们也对此感到悲伤
Also, we feel sad about that, as you can see.
现在是好消息
Now for some good news.
- 我们非常激动地...  - 够了 唐
- We are very excited...  - All right, Don.
我是泰德·亨德里克斯 过渡期的主管经理
Ted Hendricks. Managing director of the transition.
眼下的形势 并不乐观
Never fun, this stage.
但我们确实获得允许来出版...
But we do have ahead of us the privilege of publishing...
这最后一期的"生活"月刊杂志
what will be the very last issue of LIFE magazine.
而这最后一期 我们刚刚收到了一封电报
And for the final issue, we just received a telegram.
给我
Come on.
肖恩·奥康奈尔发来的...
From Sean O'Connell...
据说他从不愿意...
who has never, I'm told, been willing...
和公司的高管接触
to speak with the executives here.
然而这次 他打破了长期的沉默
Well, he broke his long silence
跟我们分享了他的想法...
and shared his thoughts with us...
通过那位老伯
through that old man.
我是肖恩·奥康奈尔
Sean O'Connell.
"我希望能以二十五号底片作为封面"
"I expect full consideration of negative 25 for cover."
"我最高的杰作"
"My most grand."
"生活的精髓"
"The quintessence of life."
精髓是啥?
What is that?
好像是指充实而富有
It means like the fullest and most rich.
好了 因此我们下一期封面将会非常轰动...
Okay. So our cover will probably be the most famous ever...
因为它真的蕴含生活的精髓
because it really will have the big quintessence of all time.
充实而富有
Very full and so rich.
那么让我们见识一下 怎样?
So let's see this thing. Huh?
看下那照片
Let's see it.
我们... 我现在在这里干什么? 下面该怎么办?
Can we... What am I doing up here? What's going on?
我们现在向底片资产部拿到这个底片
We'll receive it now from Negative Assets.
就是那位先生 最后一个进来的
This gentleman. The last man in.
底片资产部 那是什么?
Negative Assets. What's that?
啊 汤姆上校
Ah, Major Tom.
能把照片给我吗?
Can I get that?
底片还在处理中
It's being processed.
好的 那现在开工吧
All right. Well, let's do it.
去搞定那生活的精髓吧
Let's process some quintessence.
开始吧
Come on.
行动起来
Go.
马上
Now.
这就是拍手的原因
That's why I'm clapping.
- 我们什么时候印刷?  - 两周半后
- When do we go to press?  - Two and a half weeks.
你好
Hi.
我叫华特
I'm Walter.
我叫谢尔
Cheryl.
- 米蒂  - 梅霍芙
- Mitty.  - Melhoff.
没错
Yes.
- 你在摄影师账户部工作 是吗?  - 是的
- You work in Photo Accounts, right?  - I do.
你在底片资产部
Negative Assets.
是的
Yes. I am.
你在处理最后一期封面照片 那可是件大工程
You're processing the last cover photo. That's a big deal.
是的 这个... 有一点... 我们遇到一点困难
Yeah, it's... there's a... we have a glitch.
一点点小问题
Mini, on that one right now.
我想跟你说...
I wanted to say, to you...
你有没有肖恩·奥康奈尔的住址?
do you maybe have an address for Sean O'Connell?
唔... 这可能不好找
Um... It's not really that easy with him.
他居无定所 我不知道
He moves around so much. I don't.
是啊 他是自由投稿者
Yeah, he's on a freelance.
我不知道他的住址 而且他也没有电话
I don't know where and he doesn't have a phone.
- 没有电话? 他很传统  - 是的
- No phone? He's old school.  - Yeah.
对了 我去找佩吉查一下吧?
But, you know, why don't I check with Peg?
她刚刚准备了一张给肖恩的支票
I know she just processed a check for him.
我们也许可以查送信地址 用这种方式找他?
And we could track his pay-out maybe. Find him that way?
- 很好 太好了  - 好的
- Cool. Very cool.  - Okay.
- 你叫华特  - 是的
- Walter.  - Yes.
我去办
I'm on it.
谢谢
Thanks.
你要进来吗?
Yes. Are you coming?
是的 不用了
Yes, I'm not.
是的 我得呆在这儿
Yes, I have to stay.
这是相版
Here's the contact sheet.
你看到什么了?
What do you see?
那送来的胶卷
This photo cluster. These three.
只有这三张是有图像的
They're the only printable ones.
这几张是他在拍25号的同时拍的
He took them around the same time he took 25.
根据这些线索可能能找到肖恩
They could give us a clue to where Sean is.
洗出这几张 好吗?
Blow them up, all right?
好的
Cool.
嘿
Hey.
华特 是吗?
Walter, right?
是的
Yeah.
我跟佩吉说了肖恩的事情了 她会回电话给我
So, I called Peg about Sean. She's gonna get back to me.
哦! 嘿 谢谢了
Oh! Hey, thanks.
好酷的眼镜 很有沙人的感觉
Cool glasses, very Sand People.
这个吗? 不是的 这是小型放大镜
These? No, these are loupes.
我工作的时候用的 它能放大...
They're for work. They magnify the...
这就是25号吗? 我能看看吗?
Is that 25? Can I see?
这个... 不是
That's... No.
我还没找到25号...
I can't quite find 25...
目前来说
just now.
你没找到?
You can't find it?
是的 所以我才想要去找肖恩
Yeah. That's why I'm trying to find Sean.
我试着根据其他的照片找到他的下落
I'm trying to track him down somehow with these other images.
他的行踪吗?
His whereabouts?
是的
Yeah.
我上过一个关于写悬疑小说的课
I take this class, Writing the Mystery Novel.
他们说关键是逆向思维
Anyway, they say the key is to work backwards.
收集所有线索 然后再各个分析
You connect the clues and then scatter them
可能看上去毫无联系
so they seem unrelated.
推理可复杂了呢
There's like a whole science to it.
- 我可以看看嘛?  - 当然
- May I?  - Sure.
好的 大拇指
Okay. Thumb.
是的 不知道是谁的
Yeah. It's an unknown thumb.
好吧 水面?
Okay. Water?
就是水吧 我猜?
Just water, I guess?
是的 就是水
Yeah, just water.
好的
Okay.
还有...
And...
好像是一个弧形...
like a curved piece of...
像是某个东西的一部分
some kind of, part of a thing.
但是我的老师说 关于线索...
But the thing with clues, my teacher says...
肯定会有一个关键
is you really only need one good one,
将所有线索联系起来...
and then they'll connect...
然后你就会觉得
and you'll be like,
"哦 是啊 当然 无名的大拇指 水面..."
"Oh, yes, of course, unknown thumb, water..."
"我早就该想到的 哈!"
"I should have seen this the whole time. Ahh!"
是啊 是啊 我会试着...
Yeah, yeah, I'll be like...
好吧 不管怎样 我该回去了 不然我就要被炒鱿鱼了
Well, anyway, I should get back and try not to get fired.
嘿 谢尔
Hey, Cheryl.
我也在做一些创作
I have something creative I've been working on, too.
哦
Oh.
就是一个小工程
Little side project.
华特 真的太美了!
Walter, it's amazing!
华特?
Walter?
我刚刚说如果佩吉给我回电话了 我会告诉你的
I was just saying I'll let you know when I hear back from Peg.
好的 谢谢
Okay. Thank you.
好的
Okay.
嘿 欧黛纱
Hey, Odessa.
什么?
What?
能否换个大点的公寓? 能放下这个钢琴的
Is there a larger apartment available the piano could fit in?
那个是我妈妈的纪念物
Because it's a memento of our mom's.
真的太大了...
That's a really big...
很多人在搬来之前都会把太大件的纪念物卖掉
Most people sell their really big mementos before they move here.
我爸爸在他们结婚那年给她买了这架钢琴
My dad bought it for her the year they were married.
对她来说意味着很多
It means a lot to her.
这是个别墅 有点儿贵...
That's a villa. It's a little more costly...
但是它绝对宽敞 有足够放得下钢琴的客厅
but it has a more generous, piano kind of size living room for you though.
好的 这个很好
Yeah. Yeah, this is good.
如果要搬进去 你需要有第一个月的
On move-in, you'd need first month's,
最后一个月的 以及全部的存款
last month's, and full deposit.
- 4700块钱  - 棒
- That's $4,700.  - Great.
好的 没问题
Yeah, okay.
- 我们会买的  - 我去拿文件
- Yeah, we'll take it.  - I'll get the paperwork.
新的别墅会在三周以后开放
The new villa comes open in three weeks.
我猜
I'm guessing.
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
弹力强人!
Stretch Armstrong!
棒极了
That's cool.
是啊 很不错不是吗?
Yeah. Isn't that awesome?
这可是你小时候最喜欢的玩具 还记得吗?
This was your favorite thing when we were little. Do you remember?
还想来一次吗?
You want to do it?
好啊
Yeah, all right.
来吧 使劲儿拉! 很好 很好!
Come on, Stretch! Good, good!
好了 我们得走了
Come on, we got to go.
一幢别墅 好吧 但是搞清楚 我可不想太奢华
A villa, okay, but hey, I'm not the Queen of Sheba.
你得有个能装得下钢琴的房间
You got to have room for your piano.
那边收拾好之前你就先住在我这边吧
You can stay at my place until it's ready.
我在这儿不会太束缚你吗?
I won't be cramping your scene?
束缚我? 不会
My scene? No.
很抱歉没让你今天住进去
And sorry we couldn't get you in here today.
华特!
Walter!
你看我找到了什么!
Look what I found!
这是你和蒂姆·林德曼的
This is from you and Tim Linderman.
你还记不记得 那时候我们收拾东西准备去欧洲玩儿?
Do you remember, we were gonna backpack Europe?
爸爸去世的那个六月?
That June Dad died?
伙计! 来看看里面有什么?
Man! What is in here?
那是我的家族盒子
That's my Walter box.
有一些咱们家的小摆设和纪念品什么的
Some of my Walter knick-knacks and keepsakes.
你做的音乐选集是最棒的!
You made the best mix tapes!
- 天啊  - 怎么了? 那是什么?
- Oh, man.  - What? What's that?
爸爸给我的旅行日志
Travel journal Dad gave me.
哦
Oh.
你应该把它捐了 因为你从来没用过 捐给贫困的小孩子吧
You should donate that, because you never used it, to a poor kid.
一个准备去欧洲旅行的贫困小孩吗?
A poor kid who's gonna travel to Europe?
你看你和你爸爸!
Look at you and your dad!
那个是我比赛的那张照片吗?
Is that my tournament one?
他对这个得意的不得了
He was so proud of this.
他真想和全世界分享你的成就
Sharing your accomplishments with the whole world.
那只是个小镇上的比赛 妈妈
It's from the Fairview Smalltowner, Mom.
我真的超喜欢那个帅帅的莫霍克头
Well, I really liked that nifty mohawk.
你知道吗 你爸爸去世后...
You know, when your daddy died...
你就去比萨店工作...
and then you went to work in that pizza place...
那家店以一个父亲命名 就是类似父亲的名字
the one that was named after a father, had that father kind of name.
棒约翰
Papa John's.
是的 送外卖
Yeah, delivery.
那个时候我就想...
And I thought perhaps that it was really sad for you...
在你爸爸去世后 在一个那样名字的店里工作
working in a restaurant named after a father
你会很难过吧
after your father just died.
我从来没往那方面想
I never even thought about that.
可能是因为我从来不叫老爸 "爸爸" 吧
Probably because I didn't call Dad "Papa."
你穿得真怪
You had a weird style.
不是我穿得怪 那个是肯德基的制服
That wasn't my style. That was a uniform. KFC.
我家勤劳的小蜜蜂
My worker bee.
"水中有字"?
"Word in the water"?
好了 知道吗? 我得走了
Okay, you know what? I got to go.
我们会让你尽快住进别墅 好吗?
We're getting you into a villa situation, okay?
- 好的  - 很好 我走了
- Okay.  - Good, everybody?
我家勤劳的小蜜蜂...
My worker bee...
- 还有我家爱表演的小蜜蜂!  - 谢谢你 妈妈
- and my performance artist bee!  - Thank you, Mom.
- 赫南多  - 嘿
- Hernando.  - Hey.
- 我什么都没看到  - 在中间偏上
- I don't see anything.  - Upper middle.
很模糊 但是水里的确有字
It's faint. There's a word in the water.
我很紧张 华特
I'm getting nervous, Walter.
嘿 这是某片海洋
Hey, this is an ocean.
那是艘船
That's a boat.
"厄基斯那克"
"Erkigsnek."
他在那艘船附近
He was near this boat.
一会儿见
See you in a few.
我去查看一下收发室
I'll check the mailroom.
终刊封面
Final cover.
责任重大啊
Big responsibility.
哦 这是我想要的照片吗?
Oh, is that my quintessence?
不是
No.
我们正在为开始做准备呢
We're prepping the wetting agents on that to start the process.
真的吗? 因为你好像还在玩玩具
Really? Because it looks like you're playing with toys.
不是 这个是礼物
No, this is a gift.
底片需要经过一系列专业的...
Yeah, the negative needs to go through a very technical...
抱歉 我没办法和你进行有关专业的对话
I'm sorry. I can't have a professional conversation with you.
你和你的金发小伙伴
You and your little blonde pal.
我们...
Let's...
你不能带着他穿过办公室
You can't walk through the office with him.
- 给我吧  - 我会收起来的
- Let's have it.  - I'll put it away.
- 把玩具给我!  - 不!
- Give me the toy, man!  - No!
现在
Now.
这是工作的地方 不是玩玩具的地方!
This is a place of business, not a place of jelly-man toys!
放手!
Get off it!
不 我不放!
No, I'm taking it!
你不能拿走我的东西
You can't just take my stuff!
那是我的! 给我!
It's mine! Give it to me!
不!
No!
别抓着我的小伙伴不放!
Stop fiddling with sweets and little men!
这才是我该做的!
I'm trying to do my job!
你是铁皮人吗?
Are you the Tin Man?
需不需要给你上点油?
Need a little oil can?
天啊
Jesus.
照片
Picture.
- 喂?  - 嘿!
- Hello?  - Hey!
- 嘿  - 怎么样了?
- Hey.  - What's up?
- 你是谁?  - 托德
- Who is this?  - Todd.
网恋网的
From eHarmony.
哦! 嗨
Oh! Hi.
那天你挂电话的时候 我是在说...
When I lost you there, I was saying...
我们需要完善你的信息 使之没有空格
we need to beef your profile up, make it, you know, not blank.
很快的 我们来创建你的"到过这里 干过那个"
Real quick, let's build your "Been There, Done Thats."
好吧 到过这里...
Okay. Been there...
呃...
Um...
我去过凤凰大学
Phoenix.
我忘了为什么去了
I forgot why.
然后是纳什维尔...
Then Nashville...
但那只是去凤凰城路过那边的机场
but that was just the airport on the way
所以我不知道算不算...
to Phoenix, so I don't know if that...
嗯哼...
Uh-huh...
嘿 伙计 我在想 如果你跟那姑娘在一起工作的话...
Hey, man, I was thinking, if you work with this girl...
为什么不直接邀请她出去呢?
why don't you just humanly invite her out?
不 不 不 我是想要试着像"椰奶鸡尾酒之歌"那样
No, no, no, I'm trying to do like a "Pina Colada Song" thing.
"椰奶鸡尾酒之歌"?
"Pina Colada Song"?
是啊 一个人发了一个广告 寻找爱人...
Yeah, you know, a guy posts an ad, looking for a lover...
然后他的妻子回复了他...
and then his wife answers it...
然后两个从不认识到一见钟情...
and it turns out they were soul mates and didn't even know it...
最后他们披着披风做爱 或是躺在披风上
and they end up making love in capes, or on a cape.
这是首歌吗? 你能唱一段吗?
It's a song? Can you sing a little bit?
如果你椰奶鸡尾酒 当被大雨淋湿
If you like pina coladas, getting caught in the rain
知道这首歌吗? 我得挂了
You know that song? I have to go.
是霍尔与奥茨的歌吗?
Is that Hall & Oates?
- 嘿!  - 嘿
- Hey!  - Hey.
又有新线索了吗?
Is that another clue?
- 是啊 这个线索很不错  - 是吗?
- Yeah. This one's okay.  - Yeah?
我想这里有一艘船
There's a boat there, I think.
- "厄基..."  - 斯那克
- "Erkig..."  - Snek.
- 厄基斯那克?  - 是的
- Erkigsnek?  - Yeah.
听起来确实是个好线索
Sounds like a real clue.
是啊 那是个船的名字
Yeah, it's the boat's name.
你在谷歌上搜过了吗?
Have you Googled it?
正准备去查
I was on my way to.
是的 NU
Yeah. N-U.
是港口城市的首字母
It's the first two letters of the port city.
正在查询
Buffering.
那么 我得...
So, the park...
我得去趟公园接我儿子
I got to run up there and pick up my son.
他在和朋友滑滑板
He's skateboarding with a friend.
你要和我一起走吗?
Do you want to walk up with me?
现在吗?
Starting now?
是的 现在就走
Yeah, starting now.
好的
Okay.
我们得把这事儿弄清楚 这是个大事儿
Yeah, we got to figure this out. It's a big deal.
你得找到肖恩·奥康奈尔
You lost a Sean O'Connell.
我以前在纳贝斯克工作
I used to work at Nabisco.
然后 我的生活发生了点变化...
And then, I had a change...
我决定申请来生活杂志工作
and I decided to apply to LIFE.
想着这边应该会更丰富多彩 少些局限 我猜是这样
Thought it would be more colorful, less regular, I guess.
你知道 我只是喜欢它的理念
You know, I just like the idea of it.
我喜欢公司的那句格言
I like the motto of the company.
你知道吗?
Do you know it?
"认识世界..."
"To see the world..."
"克服困难..."
"Things dangerous to come to..."
"洞悉所有..."
"To see behind walls."
我...
Yeah, I...
肖恩送我的礼物
I got this, from Sean.
他给你的?
He gave this to you?
是的
Yeah.
我喜欢这句 "感受彼此"
I like that, "To draw closer."
那么 他是个什么样的人?
So, what's he like in person?
- 肖恩?  - 是的
- Sean?  - Yeah.
呃 说实话我没见过他
Well, I haven't actually met him.
我是说 我们经常聊天 但是...
I mean, we talk a lot, but...
我从一开始就负责和他联系的
I've been his point guy here ever since I started.
这是多久以前的事儿?
How long ago was that?
16年前
16年前?
天啊 哇哦
Oh, my gosh. Wow.
你一点也不担心
Well, you have nothing to worry about.
我是说裁员的事情
With the layoffs, I mean.
我到这儿一个月了
I've been here for a month.
"新人先滚蛋" 不是吗?
"Last in, first out," right?
哦 抱歉
Oh. Sorry.
是理查的爸爸
It's Rich's dad.
那就是你的...
It's your...
前任老公 刚刚离的
Former. Newly former.
但是我们还是... 我也不知道
But we've been sort of... I don't know.
我不用接
I don't need to get it.
那么 你儿子玩的是哪种滑板呢?
So, what kind of skateboard does your son have?
呃 我也不知道!
Um, I have no idea!
就是长长的 我也不知道是什么
It's oblong. I don't know.
- 干嘛问这个?  - 没有 我只是...
- Why?  - No, I just...
我以前... 我以前也玩过
I used to... I was kind of into the scene.
- 你玩过滑板?  - 是的
- The skateboard scene?  - Yeah.
哇哦!
Wow!
嗨 佩吉
Hi, Peg.
是的 就是肖恩·奥康奈尔 我们得找到他
Yeah, it's Sean O'Connell, we actually need to find him.
是的 如果你能尽快的话
Yes. If you could hurry.
翻板
Kickflip.
是的
Yeah.
这个是保留节目的经典动作
It's a good one for the repertoire.
我是华特
I'm Walter.
我是理查
Rich.
是的 我想他可能知道点儿什么或者有什么对我们有用的东西
Yeah, we think he might know something or have an asset we need.
知道吗 你只要在用一点劲儿...
You know, you just got to get a little more snap...
让滑板起得来
get that thing up there.
要我给你示范一下吗?
Want me to show you something?
好吧
Sure.
给
Here.
我喜欢你的滑板
I like your trucks.
谢谢
Thanks.
现在来看看这个
Now check this out.
- 知道怎么跳吗?  - 嗯哼
- Know about the flick?  - Uh-huh.
是的 我们已经处理完他四月份的工作订单了
Yeah, we've finished processing his April work order.
是的 这个很重要
Yes, it's kind of important.
税表你也发送过去了?
Did you forward the job 1090s?
他最后的工资你也预填了?
Or his last salary?
哇哦!
Wow!
- 还给你  - 这太屌了
- Here you go.  - That was awesome.
所以哪里都有可能
So it could be either place.
- 谢谢 华特  - 好的 谢谢 佩吉
- Thanks, Walter.  - Okay. Thanks, Peg.
好的
All right.
嘿 情况是...
Hey, so...
肖恩肯定不在纽约
Sean's definitely not in New York.
佩吉说她发送了好几份出去
Peg said she sent multiples.
我不确定你知不知道他的习惯
I don't know if you know how it works with him.
因为我们都不知道他在哪里 所以她发了好几份出去
She sends copies because we never know where he's gonna be.
这次她把税表发到新泽西的普林斯顿
And this week she sent 10903 to Princeton, New Jersey.
这方便啊 火车直达
Oh, great. Train ride.
而另一个发去了格陵兰
And one to Greenland.
以保万一
Just in case.
格陵兰 丹麦那个?
Greenland, the country?
那就...
That's...
不是火车的距离了
You can't take a train there.
是啊
No.
- 他也可能在新泽西  - 对啊
- Well, maybe he's in Jersey.  - Yeah.
对了 你手机搜索那船名有结果了吗?
Yeah, is your phone done buffering with that ship's name?
读取好了! 看这里
Yes! Look. Here it is.
在格陵兰岛的努克
Nuuk, Greenland.
好哎!
Yeah!
拜托 这线索不错的!
Come on, that's a good lead!
你应该进一步跟进
You should follow that up.
是啊 一路跟去格陵兰
Yeah, follow it up in Greenland.
是啊 怎么了? 追过去啊!
Yeah. Why not? Go!
破解谜案
Crack the case.
钱包上的字就是你的心声
Listen to your wallet.
对不起 是... 菲尔又打过来了
Sorry, it's my... it's Phil again.
他估计有麻烦或者什么事了 我还是接一下比较好
Maybe he fell down a well or something. Maybe I should get it.
嘿 伙计! 过来!
Hey, buddy! Here!
理查 理查! 别这么快! 过来!
Rich, Rich! Not so fast! Here!
这个你拿着
Take that.
好的 我知道了
Yeah. I understand.
好的 再见
Okay. Bye.
他的确惹了些麻烦
He did fall down a well.
但我不在乎
But I don't care.
我只想和你在一起 懂吗?
I just want to be with you, you know?
真的?
Really?
我们私奔吧 让我们活在当下 立刻马上
Let's run away together. Let's make every moment count, starting now.
好极了!
Sweet!
我能跟你说件事吗?
Can I tell you something?
任何事都行
Anything.
我喜欢"奇幻逆緣"那种设定
I have that Benjamin Buttons thing.
年纪越老 体格变得越小
Where you get old, but smaller.
反正就这意思 最后 变成一个外表老头的婴儿
Or whatever, and become a gradual old baby. Or something.
我没看过那电影 所以确切的细节也不太清楚
I didn't see the movie, so I don't really know how it works.
但我买了碟片
But I have it.
就算这样 我们也能一起生活在一起
We can still build a life together.
爽
Cool.
我喜欢你这件可爱的小衬衫
I like your snappy little suit.
我在玩偶店买的
I bought it at a doll store.
哦 很好啊
Oh. Cool.
我的小心脏已经不足硬币大小...
My little heart is no bigger than a quarter...
但里面却很充实
but it's as full as Fort Knox.
你是我见过最勇敢的人
You're the bravest man I've ever known.
我爱你 宝贝
I love you, baby.
不是"婴儿" 而是...
Not like "baby," like...
因为你长的就像一个奇怪的婴儿一样
because you look like a little weird baby-man.
我懂的
I get it.
谢谢你给了我如此美满的人生
Thank you for such a wonderful life.
静静地躺着 走完这一世吧
Just nestle in here and die.
再见 华特
Good-bye, Walter.
再见了! 华特!
Good-bye! Walter!
华特! 华特!
Walter! Walter!
- 再见!  - 哦!
- Bye!  - Oh!
不好意思! 我只是有点...
Sorry! I was just...
你要去哪里?
Where do you go?
我刚刚在想...
I started thinking about...
算了 没事 估计我的破冰箱的事情也无聊到你了
No, it's okay, I was probably boring you about my broken refrigerator.
没有的事!
No!
理查!
Rich!
我儿子快跑远了 我要走了
My son's running into the street. I have to go.
好的
Yeah.
跟你说件事 那首"汤姆上校"
I wanted to tell you, that song, "Major Tom"?
之前 那个大胡子...
Back there, when the beard guy was...
他根本不知道他在说什么
He doesn't know what he's talking about.
那首歌讲的是勇敢和对未知的探索
That song is about courage and going into the unknown.
很赞的一首歌
It's a cool song.
理查!
Rich!
哟!
Yo!
我的东西呢?
Where's my thing?
浸在银盐液槽里了
It's in a silver bath.
我都不知道你在说哪门外星语了
I don't even know what language you're speaking right now.
告诉你 你最好别给我打马虎眼
You know, you got to take me seriously.
我手上还要出版最后一期的杂志
I got a magazine to execute here.
而且还有上头的差事
And bosses to answer to.
下次我看到你的时候 照片也要在 懂了吗?
So next time I see you, I see that picture. Okay?
嘿! 白日梦的家伙!
Hey! Dream Machine!
叫你呢
Hello.
只是... 我就想确认一下你听到我说的话了
Just... I want proof you heard me.
下次我看到你...
Next time I see you...
就能看到照片
You see the picture.
这就对了!
That's right!
运气如何 赫南多?
Any luck, Hernando?
这地方都被我翻了个遍 25号照片不在这里
I turned the place upside-down. 25 is not here.
连收件室都查过了 伙计
I searched Receiving, too, man.
这不可能的!
This never happens!
我跟你说...
I'm telling you...
它不见了 华特
it's nowhere, Walter.
我的意思是 他可能就没有发过来
I mean, maybe he didn't even send it.
或者照片还在他那里
Maybe it's still on him.
华特?
Walter?
华特!
Walter!
成为一个勇敢的男人
放眼全世界
# 有些事 #
# Something filled up #
# 充实我的内心 #
# My heart with nothing #
# 有些人 教我不要哭泣 #
# Someone told me not to cry #
# 如今我已变老 #
# Now that I'm older #
# 我的心也随之冰冷 #
# My heart's colder #
# 才明白 一切不过一场骗局 #
# And I can see that it's a lie #
努克镇
嗨
Hi.
你这边还能租车吗?
Do you have any cars available?
有 我们还剩一辆蓝色和红色的
Yeah, we have a blue one and a red one.
就那辆红色的好了
I'll take the red one.
# 你曾在酒吧做服务员 #
# You were working as a waitress in a cocktail bar #
# 那是我第一次遇见你 #
# When I met you #
# 我们约会过 感动过 回首过 #
# I picked you out, I shook you up and turned you around #
# 改变了你的一切 #
# Turned you into someone new #
- 嗨  - 嗨
- Hi.  - Hi.
麻烦问一下 这里能接收信件吗?
Can I ask you, could someone receive mail here?
收件人是个美国人? 叫肖恩·奥康奈尔?
An American? Sean O'Connell?
我认为他可能把邮件地址写这里了
I think he might have received mail at this address.
你要喝一杯吗?
You want a drink?
好吧 也行啊 要不...
Okay. Yeah, I guess...
就来一小瓶好了
a small beer shoe.
所以 这里能收到信件吗?
So, could somebody get mail here?
机邮的
Heli mail.
"机邮"?
"Heli mail"?
有船路过的时候 我们用直升机把邮件送过去
We helicopter mail to the ships when they pass by.
我们这里是酒吧 也是机邮站
We are pub and helipad.
明白了 等一下 厄基斯那克号呢?
Yeah. Wait, the Erkigsnek?
是啊 厄基斯那克
Yeah. Erkigsnek.
厄基斯那克号
Erkigsnek.
我们每周二送邮过去
We flew mail to her Tuesday.
我把音量调小点
I'm gonna take it down a little, here.
我打心底说一句
I just want to speak from the heart.
我错过了一个好女人
I lost a good lady.
我觉得这首歌让我不觉得那么孤单
I feel this song is helping me feel like I'm not alone.
虽然我还是觉得很孤单
Even though I pretty much am.
来吧 我们一起唱出来
Come on, let's sing it.
大伙
Everyone.
大家一起唱
Let's sing it together.
# 你不再想我了吗 宝贝? #
# Don't you want me, baby? #
你知道一般谁送邮的吗?
Do you know who flies the mail out?
或者常飞那边的飞行员?
Do you have regular pilots?
嘿 伙计
Hey, man.
接下去 伙计
Just keep it going, man.
- 嘿  - 唱下去
- Hey.  - Sing it.
不了 谢谢 我... 我就算了
No, no, thank you. I don't... I'm all right.
快点 伙计 来吧
Come on, man. Go on.
这歌叫"我还是服务生的时候"
"I was working as a waitress"
我知道的 谢谢了 我就算了
Yeah, I know it. I'm okay. Thank you.
我因公出差 我在工作
I'm on a business trip, I'm working.
快点 伙计 这首歌对我来说很重要
Come on, man. This song is important to me.
- 没错  - 是啊
- Yeah.  - Yeah.
- 唱吧  - 好的
- Sing it.  - Okay.
# 我曾在酒吧做服务员 就这样了 #
# I was working as a waitress in a cocktail bar, that much is true #
够了吗?
Okay?
难听死了
That sucked.
做你的事去
Do your work.
推推嚷嚷的不好
You don't have to push.
- 我还戳你了 怎么着?  - 住手 别戳我
- What if I poke you?  - Stop. Don't poke me.
- 你敢怎么着 伙计  - 别戳我!
- Do your work, man.  - Don't poke me!
我就戳你了 我想这么着就这么着?
I'm poking you. What am I doing?
别戳我! 不准戳我!
Stop poking me! Don't poke me!
嘿!
Hey!
来啊!
Come on!
啊!
Aah!
等一下 等一下!
Wait, wait. Wait!
你的大拇指! 我要跟你谈谈你的大拇指!
Your thumb! I have to talk to you about your thumb!
没错 周二是我飞去厄基斯那克号送信的
Yeah. I flew mail out to the Erkigsnek Tuesday.
顺便捎了他一程
Gave him a ride.
我开直升机的时候 他拍了我的手
He took that photo of my hand on the stick.
不敢相信 我竟然找到这大拇指的主人了
I'm just blown away I located your thumb.
那个 其实格陵兰岛大概就七八个人
There is, like, eight people in Greenland.
我是想说 这里比对大拇指 简单明了
I mean, it's a good place to find a thumb.
别做对不起你女人的事情 伙计...
Don't cheat on your lady, man...
特别是你住在一个只有八个人的地方
when you live in a country that only has eight people in it.
就这么一说
By the way.
所以...
So, uh...
你也有点脾气的啊
You're scrappy.
你是个有点脾气的小伙子
You're a little scrappy Duncan.
所以你在找这个人?
So, you're trying to find this guy?
是的
Yes. Yeah.
五分钟之后 我就要送些电台零件过去
Well, I'm flying some radio parts out there in five minutes.
他可能还在船上
He may still be on the boat.
- 真的?  - 有可能
- Really?  - Yeah.
你也许跟我一起走也不错
Maybe you could come with me.
可以 也许我可以直接打他的船载电话
Yeah, or maybe I could just call him on the boat phone.
船载电话?
The boat phone?
嗯 船上的电话
Yeah, the phone on the boat.
你是指联络装置?
You mean the ship-to-shore?
是的 估计用联络装置也蛮方便的
Yeah, maybe I could just ask him on the ship-to-shore.
他们的电台坏了
Their radio is broke.
所以我才要飞这么一趟的
That's why I'm flying out there now.
哦
Oh.
你现在就准备走?
You're flying out right now?
喝完这杯我就出发
I'm just gonna finish my beer.
可天气看起来不怎么样啊
The weather doesn't look so great.
的确不怎么样
It's not.
那边的风暴看上去要飘过来的样子
Looks like there's a storm moving in.
是啊
Yeah.
大风暴
A-brewin'.
没错
Yeah.
但你刚刚...
But you're just...
你刚刚喝过酒...
you're just gonna finish your beer...
还能飞得稳吗?
and then fly a machine?
也对哦
Yeah.
风暴来了 我稍微有点紧张而已
I'm kind of nervous about the storm.
所以就来这边喝酒压压惊
I just want to get a couple of beers down.
好吧 那我不跟你走了
Okay. I'm not gonna go with you.
好吧
Yeah.
随便你
Whatever.
- 再见了  - 走好
- See you, man.  - Okay.
再见
See you.
好吧
Okay.
别叫了!
Shut up!
嗨 大家好
Hi. Hello, everyone.
嗨...
Hi. Uh...
你好啊 努克镇
Hello, Nuuk.
不好意思 有点小紧张
Sorry, I'm a little nervous.
好嘞
Okay.
这首歌送给华特·米蒂
This one goes out to Walter Mitty.
他懂的
He knows why.
# 塔台呼叫 汤姆上校 #
# Ground Control to Major Tom #
# 打起精神 戴上头盔 #
# Take your protein pills and put your helmet on #
# 塔台呼叫 汤姆上校 #
# Ground Control to Major Tom #
# 起飞倒计 引擎启动 #
# Commencing countdown, engines on #
# 检查点火 #
# Check ignition #
# 上帝保佑你 #
# And may God's love be with you #
# 塔台呼叫 汤姆上校 #
# This is Ground Control to Major Tom #
# 你创造了历史 #
# You've really made the grade #
# 报纸想报道你的事迹 #
# And the papers want to know whose shirts you wear #
# 也该大着胆子 出去闯一闯了 #
# Now it's time to leave the capsule if you dare #
# 汤姆上校 呼叫塔台 #
# This is Major Tom to Ground Control #
# 我已经不再退缩 #
# I'm stepping through the door #
# 我已经在传奇旅行的路上 #
# And I'm floating in the most peculiar way #
# 今晚星空奇特非常 #
# And the stars look very different today #
# 我坐着宇宙飞船 #
# For here am I sitting in a tin can #
# 离开故土 越来越远 #
# Far above the world #
# 地球是蓝色的星球 我已经飘然而去 #
# Planet Earth is blue and there's nothing I can do #
嘿
Hey.
你能来挺好的
Glad you came.
坐着舒服吗?
Are you comfortable?
什么?
What?
坐着舒服吗?
Are you comfortable?
怎么可能!
No!
抓稳了
Hold on tight.
嗨 这船就是了!
Hey, there she is!
我们怎么降落?
Where do we land?
不需要!
We don't!
什么?
What?
我们不需要降落
We don't land.
好了 华特
Okay, Walter.
我本来打算直接把电台部件扔进船里的
I was gonna drop the radio parts into the boat.
现在你跟它们一起吧 东西就放在你旁边
You take them. They're right next to you.
- 这包?  - 是的
- These?  - Yeah.
跳到船上去就行 懂了吗?
Just jump in the boat. You got them?
- 直接跳船上?  - 是的
- Just jump in the boat?  - Yeah.
是的 你能行的 华特!
Yeah, you're doing great, Walter!
你说"直接跳船上"是什么意思?
What do you mean, "jump into the boat"?
我以后怎么联系你好呢?
What would be the best way of reaching you to stay in touch?
我不知道 等等!
I don't know. Wait!
"直接跳上去"到底什么情况?
What do you mean "jump into the boat"?
我们离船还很远呢!
It looks far away!
没错 但你还是要跳了!
Yeah, but you got to go now!
跳 跳 速度跳!
Go, go, go!
跳啊!
Go!
搞错了!
No!
不 华特!
No, Walter!
我是说另一艘船! 那艘小的!
I meant the other boat! The little boat!
救命!
Help!
救命! 救命!
Help! Help!
保持冷静
Try to remain calm.
皮划艇马上来救你了
The pontoon boat is coming for you.
你至少还有一分钟 那之后你才会冻住!
You have at least a minute before you freeze!
什么?
What?
你是安全的!
You are safe!
这里有个东西!
There's something here!
这有个带鱼鳍的!
There's a fin here, I think!
我们在穿过海豚群!
We are traveling through a porpoise school!
别担心 那是海豚!
Don't fear the porpoise!
我觉得那不是海豚!
I don't think it's a porpoise!
放心 就是海豚
I'm telling you, it's a porpoise.
友好点
Be friendly.
它会保护你 防止鲨鱼咬你
It will protect you from the sharks.
好吧
Okay.
快来
Come here.
嘿!
Hey!
嘿
Hey.
好吧 那是鲨鱼
Okay, that's a shark.
我早就说是鲨鱼了!
That's what I said!
天啊!
Jesus!
别招引它了!
Stop befriending it!
宰了它!
Kill it!
这不是海豚!
It's not a porpoise!
戳它的眼睛!
Poke his eyes out!
打它!
Fight it!
天啊
Oh, my God.
我没做梦吧?
That really happened?
脸是真的
Real face.
不好意思 摸了你的脸
Sorry for palming your face.
天啊
Oh, my God.
一艘引航船来过
A pilot boat came.
四小时前把他接走了
They took him four hours ago.
就在风暴之前
Before the storm.
接去哪了?
Took him where?
冰岛
Iceland.
有什么办法可以联系到他吗?
Is there any way that we could radio him?
我有很重要的事要问他
It's very important that I discuss something with him.
你刚才带着我们的电台设备跳进了海里
You jumped into the ocean with our radio components.
设备就丢了
They are lost.
没错吧?
Correct?
对 没错
Yeah, that's correct.
你是美国人?
You're American?
对
Yeah.
太棒了!
Excellent!
方兹!
Fonzie!
别这样 我给你找点干的布 伙计
Come on, I'll find you some dry clothing, homeslice.
这个行吗? 用来装你的东西?
Will this work? For your items?
完全可以 谢谢
Oh, yeah. Thank you.
嘿 我来处理这个 兄弟
Hey, I'll take this, buddy.
好
Okay.
- 饿了吗?  - 当然饿了
- Hungry?  - Sure.
我有一些超赞的蛋糕 老兄
I got some kick-ass cake, man.
谢谢
Thank you.
看着不错
Looking good.
你可以留着它
You can keep it.
嘿 这是...
Hey, this is...
这是小柑橘蛋糕
This is clementine cake.
这是小柑橘蛋糕 我妈妈做的
This is clementine cake. My mom makes this.
没错 肖恩带来的
Yeah, Sean brought it.
哇
Yeah.
好吃
Good.
5月2日 埃亚菲亚德拉 埃尔德哥斯 光圈5 尼康 85 1.4
波拉
5月16日 拉吉卡韦 布兹喀什 魔法师
这是肖恩的吗?
Is this Sean's?
对 蛋糕是他包的
Yeah, he wrapped the cake in it.
这是拍摄计划
This is a shoot itinerary.
这是一张照片的拍摄日程...
It's a field itinerary for a photo...
他说过他要去哪里吗?
Did he say anything about where he was going?
没有 他不爱说话
No, he didn't say much.
他就是给这些水手拍照
He was just taking pictures of these guys, the Chilean deckhands.
他还给我了一些建议...
He even gave me some tips...
教我怎么自拍
for my Instagrams.
脸谱加好友吧?
Facebook friends?
好啊 没问题 好
Yeah, sure. Great.
"埃亚菲拉约酷"是什么?
What is "Eyjafallajokull"?
埃亚菲亚德拉
Eyjafjallajökull.
你说什么?
Excuse me?
埃亚菲亚德拉
Eyjafjallajökull.
那是什么?
What is that?
那在冰岛 是一座火山
It's in Iceland. It's a volcano.
- 火山?  - 对
- A volcano?  - Yeah.
5月2日 就是明天
May 2nd. That's tomorrow.
你觉得有没有可能...
Do you think there's any way...
我们在冰岛停一下?
that we could possibly land in Iceland?
有啊
Yeah.
有?
Yeah?
明早我们必须得停
We have to in the morning.
太好了
Great.
因为你弄丢了电台
Because you lost the radio.
对 是啊 对不起
Right, yeah, sorry.
对不起 但那...
Sorry. But that's...
我必须得去...
Well, I just have to get to...
埃亚菲亚德拉
Eyjafjallajökull.
没错
Right.
嘿 芝麻街见了 老兄
Hey, I'll see you on Sesame Street, man.
5月2日 埃亚菲亚德拉 埃尔德哥斯
好了 你在这里 这是埃亚菲亚德拉
Okay, you're here, and this is Eyjafjallajökull.
还有15公里
It's 15 kilometers.
好了 你可以沿着海岸骑车过去
Okay. You can take the shore bike.
但你最好现在就出发 老兄
But you better get going, man.
没错 他没在那张纸上写时间
Yeah, he didn't write a time on that clue paper.
不 老兄 快走吧 因为...
No, man. Hurry. Because of...
什么? 我不懂
What? I don't understand.
他是说 老兄 你得赶紧走了...
What he means, man, is you have to hurry...
因为这里有一帮智利色鬼...
because there's a bunch of horny Chileans...
急着去脱衣舞俱乐部
who want to go to the strip club.
但这里只有一辆自行车
There's only one bike.
快跑 华特 快! 快跑! 冲啊!
Hurry, Walter, hurry! Run! Go!
冲啊!
Go!
青春永驻 骑马少年!
Stay gold, Pony Boy!
喂?
Hello?
嘿 过得好吗?
Hey, what's up?
托德? 网恋网的?
Todd? From eHarmony?
没错! 过得好吗 老兄?
Yeah! What's up, man?
一般吧 你呢?
Not much. How have you been?
挺好的 我这里现在还很早 我刚起床 老兄
Good. It's early here. I just got up, man.
我刚才一直在想你的事
I was thinking about you.
你在哪里?
Where are you?
洛杉矶
Los Angeles.
嘿 你的页面还是收不到任何示好
Hey, so your profile still hasn't received any winks.
虽然我都写了你去过凤凰城
Even though I put that you've been to Phoenix.
哦!
Oh!
我昨天从一架直升机上直接跳进了海里
I jumped out of a helicopter yesterday into the ocean.
和鲨鱼大干了一场
And had a shark fight.
好 听着 我之前提到过...
Yeah, listen, I was mentioning before...
做白日梦做多了的人 他们不是...
people who daydream too much, they're not...
不是 这是真的 我真的干了
No, it was real. I really did.
真的? "玩的就是心跳"嘛
Really? Then I'll put down "adrenaline junkie."
是哪种鲨鱼?
What kind of a shark?
嘿 托德
Hey, Todd.
我现在真的不方便接电话
I can't really talk right now.
我在去一座火山的路上
I'm on my way to a volcano.
什么玩...?
What the...?
嘿
Hey.
嗨 嘿
Hi. Hey.
你们会说英语吗?
Do you guys speak English?
我在找埃尔德哥斯街
I'm looking for Eldgos Street.
埃尔德哥斯?
Eldgos?
那是条街吧?
Is that a street?
这是埃亚菲亚德拉火山吗?
Is this Eyjafjallakuta?
发音类似这样的?
Something like that?
我觉得这家伙不知道埃尔德哥斯是什么
I don't think this guy knows what eldgos is.
这是滑板啊
It's a longboard.
没错
Yeah.
上面那是什么 是雷神索尔 还是...
What is that? Is that Thor, or...
奥丁?
Odin?
挪威的一个神? 他还蛮酷的
A Norse god? He's cool.
嘿
Hey.
你想不想做个交换?
Would you maybe want to make a trade?
我认识一个孩子 他肯定喜欢这块滑板
I know a kid who would love that board.
它很棒的 看 可以扯它
It's cool. Look, he stretches.
给 来试试扯它
Here, come here and check it out.
没错 他很有趣吧
Yeah. He's fun.
没错吧 扯起来还是很有趣的吧
Yeah, it's lots of stretching fun.
哦 哥们 我们可以用那个把你妹妹绑起来...
Oh, man. We can tie that around your sister...
想交换吗?
Want to do it?
真的?
Yeah?
太好了 太好了 谢谢
Great. Great. Thank you.
有人吗?
Hello?
嗨
Hi.
你会说英语吗?
Do you speak English?
这家旅馆关门了
The hotel is closed.
好吧 好
Okay, yeah.
我在找这个人
I'm trying to find this guy.
这个人 肖恩·奥康奈尔
This man, Sean O'Connell.
我想他可能住在这里
I think that he possibly might have stayed here.
对 对 对 我给他叫了架飞机
Yeah, yeah, yeah. I got a plane for him.
1点的时候
At 1:00.
15分钟
Fifteen minutes.
他在斯蒂基斯霍尔米机场
He's at airfield in Stykkishólmur.
是个村子 下个镇子的南部
In the valley. Next town south.
- 在哪?  - 斯蒂基斯霍尔米
- Where is it?  - Stykkishólmur.
- "蒂基斯霍米尔"?  - 对
- "Tickishoumer"?  - Yeah.
别走 别走!
No, no!
是沿着那条路一直下去吗?
Is it straight down that way?
谢谢!
Thank you!
没关系 我认识他!
It's all right, I know him!
# 来到行进火车面前 #
# Step in front of a runaway train #
# 只为再次感受活着的感觉 #
# Just to feel alive again #
# 在夜色中前行 #
# Pushing forward through the night #
# 胸膛疼痛 视线模糊 #
# Aching chest and blurry sight #
# 很远 遥不可及 #
# It's so far, so far away #
你好 你好
Hello. Hello.
快上来 快上来 埃尔德哥斯!
Come on, come on. Eldgos!
怎么回事? 大家都去哪了?
What's going on? Where is everybody?
埃尔德哥斯 埃尔德哥斯!
Eldgos. Eldgos!
Eldgos. Eldgos.
- 那是什么意思?  - 喷起
- What does that mean?  - Eretion.
喷起?
Erertion?
喷起!
Erection!
- "喷起"?  - 对 不是!
- "Erection"?  - Yes. No!
火山喷发!
Eruption!
- 火山喷发!  - 对
- Eruption!  - Yes.
肖恩
Sean.
快点! 再快点!
Faster! Go faster!
该死的! 再快点!
Holy shit! Faster!
天啊!
Oh, my God!
谢谢回来载我
Thanks for coming back for me.
真的很感谢你
I really appreciate it.
希望你找到你要找的人
I hope you find your man.
谢谢
Thanks.
嗯
Yeah.
在披萨店边上有家汽车旅馆
There's a motel near the pizza place there.
祝你好运
Good luck.
摄影师账户部
Photographic Accounts.
- 谢尔  - 我是谢尔·梅霍夫
- Cheryl.  - This is Cheryl Melhoff.
嘿 我是华特·米蒂
Hey, it's Walter Mitty.
嘿 大概一小时前 我过去
Hey. I'd walked down to say hi to you
跟你打声招呼 但你不在
about an hour ago, and you weren't there.
那是因为 你猜
That's because, guess what.
我在冰岛
I'm in Iceland.
冰岛?
Iceland?
等等 不该是格陵兰岛吗?
Wait, wasn't it Greenland?
对 没错 本来是的
Yeah. Yeah, it was.
你应该知道这是两个不同的岛吧
You know that they're not the same place.
知道 知道 我确实去了格陵兰岛 然后...
No, no, no. I went to Greenland and then...
我上了一条渔船 追踪肖恩 然后就到了冰岛
I got on a fishing vessel tracking Sean and ended up here in Iceland.
你在冰岛
You're in Iceland.
对啊 在棒约翰披萨店
Yeah. At a Papa John's.
嘿 我找到了更多的线索
Hey, I got more clues.
你找到了什么?
What did you find?
肖恩在蛋糕包装纸上写了一个日期
There's a date that Sean wrote.
还有其他的单词
And some words on a cake wrapper.
"拉吉卡韦" "布兹喀什"...
"Rajqawee," "Buzkashi"...
还有"魔法师"
and "Warlocks."
等等 冰岛还有棒约翰披萨店呢?
Wait. They have a Papa John's in Iceland?
对啊 我刚得去... 我刚走
Yeah. I just had to... I just left.
你是不是被赶出去了?
Did you get kicked out?
不是 我只是得走了
No, I just needed to leave.
就是不喜欢那里的气氛
Just the atmosphere.
还有杯子
And the cups.
嘿 肖恩的线索我理解的是对的
Hey, I was right on Sean's trail.
然后我就追丢了
Then I lost him.
"强壮的小矮人"
"Strong little man."
谢谢
Thanks.
不是 "拉吉卡韦"的意思是在40个阿拉伯国家里的...
No. "Rajqawee" means "strong little man"...
"强壮的小矮人"
in, like, 40 Arabic countries.
"布兹喀什"是中非的...
And "Buzkashi" is "goat hockey"...
"山羊曲棍球"
in Central Asia.
还有"魔术师"...
And "warlocks"...
对
Yeah.
我希望它们是有联系的
I was hoping they would connect.
你刚才说你因为那里的杯子就离开了棒约翰?
So, you said that you left Papa John's because of the cups?
那我作为消费者是不是该知道些什么?
Is there something I should be aware of as a customer?
不是 我之前在那里干过 就这样
No, I just worked there, that's all.
我以前留着莫霍克头...
I used to have a mohawk...
背着双肩包...
and a backpack...
我还知道我想要成为什么 我想干什么
and this idea of who I wanted to be and what I wanted to do.
然后呢?
Yeah?
没什么 只是...
Nothing. Just...
那时 我和我爸关系特别好
I was pretty close with my dad.
他在我17岁的时候去世了 那是周二
And he died when I was 17, on a Tuesday.
那是我们没什么存款
And we didn't have any savings.
于是我在那周周四把头发剪了
So I got a haircut that Thursday...
在同一个周四我找了份工作
and a job the same Thursday.
在棒约翰?
Papa John's?
对
Yeah.
你爸允许你留莫霍克头?
Your dad let you have a mohawk?
他亲自给我剃的
He shaved my head.
真是个好爸爸
That's a good dad move.
对啊
Yeah.
冰岛美吗?
Is it nice there?
嗯 挺美的
Yeah, it is.
真的很美丽
It's really beautiful.
这边可一点都不美好
Well, it's pretty sucky here.
人力资源部已经开始
Human Resources has already started
裁掉一些员工了...
letting some of the staff go...
等你回来的时候会有很大不同
so it'll be a lot different when you get back.
嘿 我弄了点东西 给...
Hey, I picked something up for...
我想刚才信号不好
I think I lost you.
这样吧 回去再细聊
You know what? I'll catch up with you when I see you.
好啊
Great. Okay.
好的 没问题
All right. Okay.
拜拜 华特
Bye, Walter.
回见 谢尔
Bye, Cheryl.
赫南多发来短信: 十万火急 小胡子再见不到你 他就要炒我了
怎么了?
What's going on?
他们关了两层楼
They shut down two floors.
你怎么这么狼狈?
Why do you look rugged?
我看见你了
I see you.
又见面了!
I see you!
我上次说啥?
What did I say?
我看见你了
I see you.
照片 拿出来
The photograph. Now. Let me see it.
我让他查了 没有什么叫银盐溶液的玩意
He looked it up. There's no such thing as a silver bath.
听着 底片这东西很容易出问题
Listen, there was uncertainty about the negative.
我明白 但底片在冰岛
I understood that, hopefully, it was in Iceland.
这是你的事
It was in your care.
你再给我点时间...
If you just give me some more time...
你被开除了
You're fired.
我们换别的封面
We'll make another cover.
等等!
Hey!
我处理过的底片成百上千
More than a million, way more, negatives have come through my office.
从没印错过一个
I have never mislaid one.
写块匾 挂在你的下一个办公室里
Put it on a plaque. Hang it at your next job.
我得去和董事会解释了
Now I got to explain this to the board?
嘿
Hey.
你还好吧?
Are you okay?
还好
Yeah.
挺酷啊
That's cool.
滑板 送给谢尔的儿子的
It's a skateboard. It's for Cheryl's son.
谢尔不在 她被裁了
Cheryl's not in. She was let go.
很抱歉
I told you, man, it's bad.
等等! 那是我的花
Hey! That's my fern.
谢谢
Thank you.
嗨
Hi.
你好
我能...?
Can I...?
呃
Yeah.
我找谢尔·梅霍夫
I'm looking for Cheryl Melhoff.
找谢尔?
You want Cheryl?
她...
Yeah. She's...
我们是同事 她帮我处理了点公事
We work together, and she was helping me with a work thing.
谢尔
Cheryl.
亲爱的?
Honey?
有人找你
There's some guy here.
什么?
What?
你同事
From work.
等等啊 等我打完电话
Okay, hold on. I'm on the phone.
欢迎收看柯南秀
It's Conan.
今晚的嘉宾是第一夫人米歇尔·奥巴马和华特·米蒂
Tonight, First Lady Michelle Obama, Walter Mitty.
我们来谈谈你的感情?
Can we talk about your love life?
大家肯定很感兴趣
I think people would be interested.
你们不会想知道的
You don't want to know about my love life.
绝对想啊
I think they do.
必须想 我再也不相信小道消息了
Yeah, I think they do. Now, I don't believe everything I read.
你闹了点丑闻?
There's a scandal? A little scandal?
一桩小丑闻 没错
A little scandal, yes.
她和她丈夫复合了
She was back with her husband, or something.
然后她爱上你了?
Then she fell for you?
无风不起浪
Where there's smoke, there's fire.
你太棒了 华特
You're awesome, Walter.
多谢
Thanks.
必须的
Sure.
能把这个关了吗?
Can you turn this off?
不行
It stays on.
那让我下车
I'm just going to get out.
嗨 妈妈
Hey, Mom.
嗨 亲爱的
Hi, honey.
华特 你得给他们小费
Walter, you got to tip these guys.
我们把钢琴安全带回来了
We got the piano back safe, Mom.
刚出差回来吗?
Are you back from your work trip?
是啊 早上回来的
Yeah, this morning.
饿吗?
Hungry?
有点
Mmm-hmm.
- 我做了汤  - 谢谢
- I'm making soup.  - Thanks.
现在给小费吧
Hey, tipping time now.
我就这些了
This is all I got.
谢谢 非常感谢
Thank you. Thank you very much.
没事 谢了
All right, thanks, everybody.
辛苦了
For all your hard work.
非常感谢 夫人
We appreciate it, ma'am.
你们做得很棒 我就不送了
You did great. You just let yourself out.
他这样就好
He's good for this.
留下吃晚饭吗?
Are you gonna stay for dinner?
我也想啊 妈
Oh, Mom, I'd love to.
这一天监工当的
I think I'm just really wiped out
快累死我了
after supervising moving that thing all day.
我去练练瑜伽 然后闷头睡一觉
I think I just need to go to yoga and then just crash.
那是啥东西? 课?
What is it? A class?
是啊 瑜伽课
Yes, yoga.
是门课 我选的是热瑜伽 屋子里温度很高
It's a class. I go to the hot kind, where they heat the room.
- 你听说过吗?  - 当然
- Have you heard of that?  - Sure.
听过啊? 很有好处的
You have? It's great for you.
练一练可轻松了
You just get it all out of your system.
出出汗 把所有烦恼都忘掉
You get your sweat out, you just get everything, all your fear.
我在等一个试镜的通知
I'm waiting on a call about an audition.
"火爆浪子"吗?
That Grease show?
- 是啊  - 演里佐?
- Yeah.  - Rizzo?
是啊 我很期待
Yeah. I'm really excited about it.
练瑜伽的时候什么都不会想
What's good about this is that I just don't worry about it.
抛开杂念
I just get out of my head.
那不是挺好的?
Is that good for you?
我觉得报个班上上挺好的
I feel like it's good in a class like this.
虽然得不到什么报酬 但是无所谓
I mean, I'm not going to get paid for it, which is fine.
- 和钱无关  - 多好啊
- It's not about money.  - Wonderful.
我觉得...
And I feel like...
那课是给孩子们上的 从小开始练很重要
It's just for kids, but I think it's important for them to start early.
我挺激动的 妈
I'm really thrilled, Mom.
自己享受就行
I think I'm just going to enjoy it.
站在大家面前讲话
Just standing in front of people and talking.
- 你会得心应手的  - 是啊
- You'll be good at that.  - Yeah.
- 你会很棒的  - 我也觉得 妈
- You'll really be good at that.  - I think so, too, Mom.
妈?
Hey. Mom?
怎么了
Yeah.
有人给你的钢琴拍过照吗? 大概一周以前
Did somebody take a picture of your piano, like, a week ago?
我照过
I did.
用肖恩的相机
With Sean's camera.
肖恩·奥康奈尔的相机?
Sean O'Connell's camera?
是啊 他来过
Yeah, he came to visit.
什么?
Mom, what?
没错啊
Yeah.
他想了解你的行程
He wanted to know about your work schedule,
你什么时候走 什么时候回家
when you left, when you came home.
他说你真的很懂"生活"杂志的真谛
He said you really understood LIFE.
他对你的工作很感兴趣
He was really interested in your work.
妈 你怎么不告诉我?
Mom, why didn't you tell me?
我说了啊 买菜的时候给你说的
I told you. I told you in the produce aisle.
我还记着呢
I remember that.
可能你...
Maybe you were...
欧黛莎 你怎么形容他走神?
Odessa, what is it you call it when he goes into one of his little places?
"迷糊"
"Zoned out."
你时不时就犯迷糊
You do that now and then.
怎么了?
What's the matter?
我被开除了
I got fired.
我把他的照片丢了
I lost a picture of his.
能找到吗?
Can you find it?
找不着了 我不知道他在哪
No, I don't know where he is.
他去找魔法师还是什么的...
He's someplace with warlocks or...
是军阀
Warlords.
不 魔法师
No, warlocks.
不是 是军阀
No. Warlords.
肖恩说他很快会去见军阀...
Sean said he had to meet with warlords very soon...
没准带着我的蛋糕
and maybe he would take my cake
能买通他们...
so that he could get permission...
好去野外拍照
to trek through the wilds and places.
他说他要去拍雪豹 厉害吧?
He said he wants to photograph snow leopards. How about that?
谁?
Who?
"混乱的阿富汗"
"Ungoverned Afghanistan."
没错
Mmm-hmm.
肖恩就在那
That's where Sean is.
混乱的阿富汗 没错
Crazy Afghanistan. Yeah.
在喜马拉雅山脉上
In the upper Himalayas.
他们不会赶你走
They can't let you go.
你是肖恩的搭档
You were Sean's partner.
他告诉我...
He told me...
你是最努力按他的设想...
that you were the person who worked the hardest...
帮他完成作品的人
to make sure his work was realized the way he wished.
去完成他的作品吧
You finish his work.
五月八日 喜马拉雅山下
# 天堂是你总想到达的地方 #
# Heaven is a switchboard that you want to fight #
# 如果你愿意帮她开阔眼界 她会想你 #
# She would even miss you if you taught her sight #
# 当政治家们开始右倾 #
# Power politician leaning to the right #
我雇了两个强壮的小男人
# 当孩子们有了信用基金 #
# Baby's got a trust fund #
# 她就会离开 #
# That she'll want to go off like that #
# 不再烦恼 #
# Get off of my stack #
# 开一扇小窗 #
# Leave a little window #
# 不再烦恼 #
# Get off of my stack #
我接受了"山之洗礼"
# 现在我们穿着一样的黄衣服 #
# Now we wear same-colored yellow uniforms #
我们用妈妈做的蛋糕贿赂了军阀
# 天空在燃烧 但是我们却很温暖 #
# Sky is burning but at least we know we're warm #
# 走遍了全世界 #
# Go and run yourself a million miles #
# 希望这个颜色最终会消失 #
# Hoping that the colors run out #
# 然后你也会像我一样
# And you go off like that #
# 远离烦恼 #
# Get off of my stack #
# 烦恼 #
# Stack #
身体和心灵的测试
海拔18000英尺
我的意识像雪一样在漂
我孤身一人
一个人
嘿 托德
Hey, Todd.
怎么样?
Hey, what's up?
还好
Not much.
好消息 你的档案终于完成了
Hey, good news. Your profile really rounded out, man.
多亏了火山鲨鱼一条龙
That volcano-shark combo.
简直是香饽饽 等着姑娘来找你吧
That is money in the bank. Get ready to get a lot of winks.
那好啊
Okay.
但是还有件事
But something else.
谢尔·梅霍夫...
Cheryl Melhoff...
她不在这了 注销了
she's not on here anymore. Withdrawn.
哦
Oh.
- 真的?  - 是啊
- Really?  - Yeah.
你现在在哪?
Hey, man, where are you now?
喜马拉雅
Himalayas.
喜马拉雅 我爱死那地方了
The Himalayas. I love it.
这是最厉害的"去过的地方"
That is a kick-ass "Been There."
托德 我得长话短说
Todd, I'm gonna keep this short.
氧气不够
I have to make oxygen choices.
我明白 冲啊!
Hey, I get it. Go!
你的档案完成了 恭喜你
Anyway, you have a profile now. Congratulations.
那不错 不过
Cool, but, you know what?
你能不能把它撤下来?
Would you take me off?
我付不起每年500的档案费
I can't really swing that $500 yearly.
等等
Hey.
哥们
Hey, man.
你确定吗?
You're sure? Because I feel like
我觉得我们才刚上道啊
we're really onto something here.
能小点声吗? 我在工作
Do you mind? I'm working.
这可是我弄过最棒的档案
This is one of the best profiles I've ever done.
关于退款的政策 我们这还没有...
And our refund policy, well, we don't have one...
托德 我得挂了
Todd, I got to go.
肖恩
Sean.
是我
Yeah.
我是华特
It's Walter.
米蒂
Mitty.
华特·米蒂
Walter Mitty.
真的?
Seriously?
你怎么上来的?
How the hell did you get up here?
我...
I just...
我一直在找你
I've been looking for you.
先坐下
Sit down.
我坐
I'll sit.
慢慢来 缓和下来
Well, take your time. Settle in.
保持安静 好吗?
Try to be real still, okay?
那有只雪豹
There's a snow leopard.
就在山脊里
Right in this ridge.
所以我们得非常非常非常安静
So we have to try to be very, very, very, very still.
大家管雪豹叫"幽灵猫"
They call the snow leopard the "ghost cat."
它们神出鬼没
It never lets itself be seen.
幽灵猫?
Ghost cat?
美好的东西从来不会寻求关注
Beautiful things don't ask for attention.
肖恩 你给我的底片有一张不见了
Sean, there was a negative that got separated from your roll.
为这事我被批了个狗血淋头
I'm taking a lot of heat over it at work.
那张底片没有寄来
It never came with the roll that you sent.
你说最后一卷?
The last roll you're talking about?
没错
Yeah.
25号
The 25.
没错
Yeah.
你就坐在它上边
You're sitting on it.
为什么这么说?
Why am I sitting on it?
就在你钱包里
It's in your wallet.
那是个礼物
That was the gift.
照片是个礼物
The photograph.
钱包只是我用来装底片的
The wallet was just something I could put it in.
我把底片放在了钱包的照片夹里
So, I put it in a little slot, the little picture holder in there.
我觉得挺有意思的
I thought it would be cute.
我告诉过你啊"往里看"
I told you, "look inside."
纸条上写了
In the note.
你说"往里看"
You said "look inside."
我以为你说的是往包装纸里看
I thought you meant look inside of the wrapping paper.
是吗? 多棒的惊喜啊
Yeah? Well, you got a real nice surprise coming.
不 没了
No, I don't have it.
已经没了
I don't have it anymore.
哇哦!
Whoa!
你在想什么啊?
What the hell were you thinking?
不好意思 我仰慕你这么久
I mean, I'm sorry, I've admired you for a very long time...
但是这真是太坑人了 那底片太珍贵了
but that is not a good move, at all, with a valuable negative.
对不起 我...
Sorry, I just...
我觉得这么挺好玩的
I thought it would be a playful kind of thing.
好玩?
Playful?
真好玩
Too playful.
我明白你的意思
I see what you're saying.
当封面的图 我应该直接给你
With the cover, I should have been more straightforward.
你要是不介意 我想问问你...
But can I ask you, I mean, if you don't mind...
钱包怎么了?
what did you do with the wallet?
扔了
Chucked it.
真伤心
Well, that hurts my feelings.
不 我很喜欢
No. Man, I liked it very much.
非常喜欢
I appreciated it very much.
所以你就把他扔了?
So you threw it away?
你不知道那是什么?
So, you have no idea what it was?
那张照片?
The photograph?
真可惜
It's a shame.
那张真的很美
It was a beauty.
话说回来 你怎么找到我的?
How did you find me, anyway?
靠我妈妈
My mom.
她是个好人 蛋糕烤得很棒
Cool lady. Knows how to bake.
是啊
Yeah.
- 你为什么...  - 嘘!
- Hey, why did you...  - Shh!
你准备什么时候拍?
When are you gonna take it?
有时候我不拍
Sometimes I don't.
如果我很喜欢某个瞬间...
If I like a moment...
我是说 就我个人而言...
I mean, me, personally...
我不喜欢为了拍照而拍照
I don't like to have the distraction of the camera.
只想享受在那一刻
Just want to stay in it.
享受在那一刻?
Stay in it?
嗯 那一刻
Yeah, right there.
就像这一刻
Right here.
现在它不见了 跑掉了
Now it's gone. It's gone.
看起来很好玩
That looks like fun.
我要加入
I think I'm gonna jump in.
嘿 那张照片是什么 肖恩?
Hey, what was the picture, Sean?
如果你不加入 我们就要落单了
We're gonna be odd-numbered if you don't join.
那照片是什么?
What was the picture?
让我们称之为鬼猫吧 华特·米蒂
Let's just call it a ghost cat, Walter Mitty.
# 你手握何物 #
# What's in your hand
# 你被囚制于常规之中 #
# You're pinned down to routines #
# 情绪时而高涨时而低落 #
# Elevate and leave #
# 闪烁的屏幕之上 #
# The flickering screen #
# 一切尽在坚持之中 #
# Where nothing is compromised #
# 一切常在 #
# Nothing is lost #
# 当一切处于意识之内 #
# When everything is realized #
# 一切顺利 #
# Nothing is crossed #
你在监视名单上
You made the watch list.
你是怎么避过旅行禁令 到阿富汗的?
How did you get to Afghanistan? There's a travel ban.
从也门过去
Through Yemen.
暴力之都
Violent place.
这就是为什么飞机票只要84美元
That's why the air fare is only $84.
我可以要回我的横笛吗?
Can I have my fife back?
你在洛杉矶认识什么人吗?
Do you know anyone in Los Angeles?
- 没有  - 一个熟人也没有? 好吧
- No.  - Any acquaintances? Okay.
同伴呢?
Any companions?
或者任何可以证明你是华特·米蒂的人?
Anybody here who might be able to verify that you're Walter Mitty?
华特·米蒂吗?
Walter Mitty?
对
Yeah.
我是托德·马哈尔 网恋网的
Todd Mahar. eHarmony.
嘿
Hey.
谢谢 谢谢
Thank you. Thanks.
什么呀? 过来
What? Come here.
过来
Come here.
双肩包包
Backpack.
大大的抱抱!
Big hug!
机场监禁 哼?
Airport prison, huh?
对
Yeah.
我们一边吃肉桂卷一边讲 来吧
Tell me all about it over a Cinnabon. Come on.
肉桂卷呀!
Cinnabon!
顺便问一句 你被拘留了多久?
How long were you detained for, by the way?
貌似有17个小时
Like, 17 hours.
哇哦! 肉桂卷味道怎么样?
Wow! How's that Cinnabon taste?
美味极了
Really great.
我的朋友 你现在吃的是糖霜海洛因
That's frosted heroin. That's what you're eating, my friend.
这就是你在这所拥有的
That's what you're having right there, man.
顺便提一下...
By the way...
在我撤下你的资料之前你得到了300个示好
you got 300 winks before I took down your profile.
在两小时之内 太疯狂了
In the space of two hours. It was crazy.
我还以为我在卖音乐会门票呢
I thought I was selling concert tickets.
我没看过
I never checked.
哦! 因为...
Oh! Because of...
那个离开的"鸡尾酒"女孩?
the "Piña Colada" girl that quit?
- 是的  - 是的
- Yeah.  - Yeah.
谢尔
Cheryl.
谢尔 从来没有回应过别人的示好...
Cheryl, who did not respond to a single wink...
她一直都在那
the whole time she was on there.
是个挑三拣四的女士
That's a choosy lady.
挑三拣四的女士啊
你的白日梦...
How's the...
进行得怎么样了?
daydreaming going?
最近比较少
Lately, less.
不错
Good.
少就是好
Less is good.
谢谢你的点心
Thanks for the pastry.
对 你欠我的
Yeah, well, you owe me.
我钢琴一卖掉 我就把支票寄给你
I'll send you a check as soon as I sell the piano.
你盘子里有很多
You have a lot on your plate.
你现在要做什么呢?
What are you gonna do now?
出去然后再找份工作
Go out and get another job.
干杯!
Boom!
对不起 华特 我只是...
Sorry, Walter, I just...
什么?
What?
你和我想象的完全不一样
You are so not how I pictured you.
你是怎么想象我的?
How did you picture me?
我想你是一个灰暗的家伙
I pictured you as a little gray piece of paper.
但现在我看到你...
But now I see you...
有点像印第安纳·琼斯...
and it's like Indiana Jones...
决定成为摇滚乐队的主唱
decided to become the lead singer
或者其他类似的
of The Strokes or something like that.
- 太疯狂了  - 我知道
- It's nuts.  - I know.
对不起 妈妈
Sorry, Mom.
为什么要说对不起?
What for?
这是爸爸买给你的 这是我的责任
Dad bought it for you. It was my responsibility.
哦 华特
Oh, Walter.
我们都在这里成长
We're all grown here.
我们都很好
We're all good.
哦欧!
Ooh!
这笔款项真是沉甸甸的责任啊
That's heavy duty, that sum.
你应该把它放在钱包里
You should put this in your wallet.
- 我没有钱包  - 喔
- I don't have one.  - Oh.
我在垃圾箱里找到的
I found it in the trash.
我一直保存着你的小东西
I always save your knick-knacks.
谢谢
Thanks.
- 妈妈 小心点?  - 知道了
- Got it, Mom?  - Got it.
小心台阶
Watch the stairs.
我认为这奏效了
I think this works.
美国之心 不同的年代 这说明了一切
Heart of America. Different generations. This says it all.
哦 嘿 欢迎
Oh, hey. Welcome.
等等 很抱歉 不欢迎
Wait, I'm sorry, not welcome.
你不是这的员工
Not an employee.
对不起
Sorry.
这是肖恩要的25号底片
There's the picture Sean wanted. 25.
你还有两天的时间印在封面上
You have two days to print for cover.
你的精华在这
There's your quintessence.
嘿
Hey.
你知道我们公司的座右铭吗?
Do you know our motto?
"生活...
"Life...
我热爱它?"
I'm lovin' it?"
不对
No.
那是麦当劳的
That's McDonald's.
泰德 你所做的这些事...
This thing that you do, Ted...
你来到一个地方 把人们挤兑走
where you come into a place and you push people out.
你应该知道那些人为了创办这本杂志
You should know that those people worked really hard
都工作得十分辛苦
to build this magazine.
他们信奉公司的座右铭
They believed in the motto.
我知道 你收到了你的裁员令...
And I get it. You got your marching orders...
你有不得已的苦衷
and you have to do what you have to do.
但是你不需要像个混蛋一样
But you don't have to be such a dick.
把它写在一块匾上 并把它挂在你的下一份工作上
Put that on a plaque, and hang it at your next job.
那是什么? 大脚野人? 还是独角兽?
What was it? Sasquatch? A unicorn?
- 底片吗?  - 对
- The negative?  - Yeah.
我没有看
I didn't look.
你是一个好上司 华特
You were a good boss, Walter.
谢谢你
Thanks, man.
发布简历
输入你的资料 上传简历以便雇主找到你
生活杂志 底片部主管 16年
证明人 肖恩·奥康奈尔(地址应请求)
非美国海军海豹突击队人员 从直升机"自由落体"到强劲的海域(北海)
一天之内 在艾雅法拉火山火山喷发时旁边进行17公里的铁人三项
攀登喜马拉雅山顶峰(面朝阿富汗西北部)
在冰岛渔船上 一天收入保持和水手长一样(无薪甲板水手)
亲爱的华特
我妈妈把你的电子邮箱给了我
所以我可以为我的滑板向你亲自道谢
非常感谢你
我的妈妈为我做了一个短片 给你看看
再次感谢你
理查德·梅霍夫
嘿 华特 你好吗?
Hey, Walter. What's up?
看看这个
Check this out.
再见!
See you!
嗨
Hi.
华特·米蒂 遣散费
Walter Mitty. Severance package.
嘿
Hey.
谢尔
Cheryl.
- 嘿  - 嘿
- Hey.  - Hey.
昨天我收到了理查德的那封邮件
I got that email from Rich yesterday.
他真的不错
He's really good.
华特 谢谢
Walter, thank you.
那是...
That was...
你做的那件事真的很酷
That was just a really cool thing to do.
我恰好在冰岛看见它
I just saw it in Iceland.
他很喜欢
He loves it.
今天下午我还要带他去
And I'm taking him this afternoon.
我想让你知道...
Hey, I wanted you to know...
你没有让我无聊
you weren't boring me.
那天在公园里
That day in the park.
我...
I was...
我当时在想...
I was thinking about...
我希望这听起来没有很怪异 但那时我是在想你
I hope this doesn't sound weird, but I was thinking about you.
当时我正在格陵兰 他们在那里唱卡拉OK...
When I was in Greenland, they do karaoke there...
而我不得不坐上一架直升机 和一个喝得醉醺醺的飞行员
and I had to get on this helicopter, with a very drunk pilot.
然后我开始想象你...
And I started to imagine you...
唱着"汤姆上校"那首歌
singing Major Tom.
不管怎样...
Anyway...
它让我上了直升机
it got me on the helicopter.
并且把我带到了我想去的地方
And it got me where I wanted to go.
所以 你发生了什么?
So, what happened to you?
你似乎失踪了
You sort of fell off the face of the Earth there.
一会会儿
For a little bit.
我路过你家然后...
I came by and...
你的丈夫开门了 所以我想我还是走吧
your husband answered so I figured I should just go.
是菲尔 他当时在修理我的冰箱
Phil. He was fixing my refrigerator.
而且他不是我的丈夫
And he's not my husband.
看起来像我想象的...
I guess I imagined...
我以为也许你们又重修旧好了
I thought maybe you got back together.
你想象力真丰富
You have a good imagination.
但是没有
But no.
嘿 我妹妹要出演"火爆浪子"
Hey, my sister got this role in Grease.
里佐
Rizzo.
不是在百老汇 在一个有点古怪的教堂里
Not on Broadway. In some weird church.
你想和我一起去看吗?
Do you want to go with me?
我知道这听起来并不是很好
I made that sound really not good.
好啊
Yeah.
好啊?
Yeah?
是啊 对 我很乐意
Yeah, yeah. I would love to.
在古怪教堂里演"火爆浪子"? 你在开玩笑吗?
Grease in a weird church? Are you kidding?
里佐 那是最好的部分
Rizzo, that's the best part.
对 里佐 铁汉柔情
Yeah, Rizzo. Tough and tender.
没错
Yeah.
太好了
Great.
你要去上城区吗?
Are you heading Uptown?
当然
Sure.
是吗?
Yeah?
事实上我一直更喜欢里佐
I actually always related to Rizzo more.
- 哦 是吗?  - 是啊
- Oh, yeah?  - Yeah.
因为抽烟还是青少年性行为?
Was it the smoking and the teenage sex?
不 我觉得她很真实
No. She was just real, I guess.
哦!
Oh!
最后版 这里应该有 它今早出版了
The last issue, it should be here. It came out this morning.
最后版 献给成就这本杂志的人
华特
Man. Walter.
我们要买一本吗?
Should we go buy one of those?
我可能会...
Yeah. I was probably gonna...
- 可能一会儿再来买?  - 对
- Probably gonna go back later?  - Yeah.
我只是想先装装酷 不想立马买一本
I just didn't want to seem uncool and get one right away.
-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=-
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 影子
翻译: Morning 脸圆圆 RK翔 汐颜 倒数第二的yjk 雪鸢域寰
校对: 千欲 秋水仙
# 这些天节奏有些匆忙 #
# There's a rhythm in rush these days #
# 生活一成不变 但是也没有因此失色 #
# Where the lines don't move and the colors don't fade #
# 让你一无所有 却保留了梦想 #
# Leaves you empty with nothing but dreams #
# 在世界之中 变得肤浅变得贫乏 #
# In a world gone shallow In a world gone lean #
# 有时候 人对于某些事总归知之甚浅 #
# Sometimes there's things a man cannot know #
# 齿轮不复转动 落叶也不复生长 #
# The gears won't turn and the leaves won't grow #
# 无处可逃 无油可加 #
# There's no place to run and no gasoline #
# 引擎不复发动 火车也不复远离 #
# Engine won't turn And the train won't leave #
# Engines won't turn And the train won't leave #
# 今夜我会伴你左右 #
# I will stay with you tonight #
# 紧紧握住你直到天明 #
# Hold you close 'til the morning light #
# 于次日之晨 看新的一天冉冉升起 #
# In the morning watch a new day rise #
# 我们会倾尽所有 只为了活一场值得的人生 #
# We'll do whatever just to stay alive #
# 我之所感及我之所写 #
# Well, the way I feel is the way I write #
# 如说谎之人的泉思如涌 #
# Racin' like the thoughts of the man who lies #
# 真理存在并且站在我们这边 #
# There is a truth and it's on our side #
# 黎明即将到来 睁开你的双眼 #
# Dawn is coming Open your eyes #
# 伴随着新的一天的到来 仰望阳光 #
# Look into the sun as the new days rise #
# 今夜我会等你 #
# And I will wait for you tonight #
# 你永远在这 在我的身边 #
# You're here forever and you're by my side #
# 我一直在等待我所有的生命 #
# I've been waiting all my life #
# 去感受你的心 随时间而跳动 #
# To feel your heart as it's keeping time #
# 我们会倾尽所有 只为了活一场值得的人生 #
# We'll do whatever just to stay alive #
# 黎明即将到来 睁开你的双眼 #
# Dawn is coming Open your eyes #
# 伴随着新的一天的到来 仰望阳光 #
# Look into the sun as the new days rise #
# 这些天节奏有些匆忙 #
# There's a rhythm in rush these days #
# 生活一成不变 但是也没有因此失色 #
# Where the lines don't move and the colors don't fade #
# 让你一无所有 却保留了梦想 #
# Leaves you empty with nothing but dreams #
# 在世界之中 变得肤浅变得贫乏 #
# In a world gone shallow In a world gone lean #
# 但是真理存在并且站在我们这边 #
# But there is a truth and it's on our side #
# 黎明即将到来 睁开你的双眼 #
# Dawn is coming, open your eyes #
# 伴随着新的一天的到来 仰望阳光 #
# Look into the sun as a new days rise #
# 走出去 我要走出去 #
# Step outside, I'm gonna step outside #
# 燃烧之心 将一切抛之脑后 #
# Heart's on fire, leave it all behind you #
# 漆黑如夜 让闪电指引前行 #
# Dark as night, let the lightning guide you #
# 走出去 我要走出去 #
# Step outside, I'm gonna step outside #
# 燃烧之心 将一切抛之脑后 #
# Heart's on fire, leave it all behind you #
# 活着的生命滋养着胃口 #
# Living life Feeding appetites #
# 每次兴致勃勃时 心脏停止跳动都是一次赌注 #
# Stake through every heart stop in the mood #
# 愉悦的 #
# Being glad #
# 以一半的时间呼吸 #
# Breathing half the time #
# 燃烧之心 将一切抛之脑后 #
# Heart's on fire, leave it all behind you #
# 漆黑如夜 让闪电指引前行 #
# Dark as night, let the lightning guide you #
# 走出去 我要走出去 #
# Step outside, I'm gonna step outside #
# 冲至周一 #
# Broke to Monday #
# 便会有所不同 #
# Something's not the same #
# 头脑一片空白 #
# Blank head #
# 交纵的瓷砖席卷了地面 #
# Cross tiles sweep the floor #
# 在不存在中感受你的存在 #
# Feel your presence in your absence #
# 关上门 #
# Shut the door #
# 燃烧之心 将一切抛之脑后 #
# Heart's on fire, leave it all behind you #
# 漆黑如夜 让闪电指引前行 #
# Dark as night, let the lightning guide you #
# 一定要坚信 #
# Must believe in #
# 走出去 走出一步 #
# Step outside Take a step outside #
# 走出一步 #
# Take a step outside #
# 一定坚信 #
# Must believe in #
# 走出去 走出一步 #
# Step outside Take a step outside #
# 走出一步 #
# Take a step outside #
# 燃烧之心 将一切抛之脑后 #
# Heart's on fire, leave it all behind you #
# 我爱你 我的女士 #
# You know I love my lady #
# 我们紧紧相依 #
# We've been together so long #
# 就像我最喜欢的歌曲唱片 #
# Like a worn-out recording #
# 最终变得磨损 #
# Of my favorite song #
# 所以当她睡在那里 #
# So while she lay there sleepin' #
# 我在床头读着杂志 #
# I read the paper in bed #
# 在个人专栏里 #
# And in the personal columns, #
# 有这样的字母 #
# There was this letter that read #
# 如果你喜欢鸡尾酒 #
# If you like piña coladas #
# 或者喜欢雨点的洗礼 #
# Or getting caught in the rain #
# 海洋的抚摸 #
# And the feel of the ocean #
# 香槟的味道
# And the taste of champagne #
# 如果你喜欢在午夜做爱 #
# If you like making love at midnight #
# 在海角的沙丘里 #
# In the dunes of the cape #
# 那么你就是我一直寻找的人 #
# Then you're the lady that I look for #
# 和我走吧 一起逃离 #
# Come with me and escape #